<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.calstfrancis.Skrizhal</id>
  <name>Skrizhal</name>
  <summary>Build a reusable YAML database of CV elements</summary>
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <description>
    <p>
      Skrizhal is a GTK4 editor for CV/résumé elements — jobs, education, awards,
      publications, service, and more — each stored as a YAML entry with a
      citation-style key. Instead of hand-typing (and hand-toggling) a new CV
      for every application, build the database once and let a style layer
      pull entries in as needed.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Sidebar with search and type/tag filtering, sorted most-recent-first</li>
      <li>Structured form for common fields (key, type, title, organization, location,
        date, tags, description), with a suggestion popover for known entry types</li>
      <li>Dynamic "Additional Fields" editor for type-specific data (degree, DOI,
        award amount, and anything else a given entry type needs)</li>
      <li>Raw YAML toggle — edit an entry's serialized block directly when the
        structured form doesn't fit</li>
      <li>Add, duplicate, and delete entries, with a confirmation before delete</li>
      <li>Manage Tags dialog — rename a tag everywhere at once, or merge two tags
        by renaming one onto the other</li>
      <li>Configurable data file location, with a guard against saving over a file
        that failed to parse</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Designed to work alongside Zerkalo, which will be able to pull entries into
      a Typst CV document in a future release.
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.calstfrancis.Skrizhal.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/calstfrancis/skrizhal</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/calstfrancis/skrizhal/issues</url>
  <developer id="io.github.calstfrancis">
    <name>Cal St Francis</name>
  </developer>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/calstfrancis/skrizhal/main/screenshots/skrizhal-main.png</image>
      <caption>Skrizhal editing a CV entry, with type-specific fields and tag filtering</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.3.1" date="2026-07-08">
      <description>
        <p>0.3.1 "Clear Ledger" — Undo/redo (Ctrl+Z / Ctrl+Shift+Z) across every mutation. New File, Open, Save As, and Preferences for managing the data file location, replacing the old open-existing-only "Choose Data File…" picker. Default data file location moved to ~/Documents/Zerkalo/cv-elements.yaml. Files with a malformed entry now load every other entry instead of failing entirely, and old files using the pre-rename `type:` field load correctly. The spreadsheet bulk-edit grid, introduced in 0.3.0, has been removed — it never replaced what it was meant to and its add-row flow could freeze the app; entries are now added and edited one at a time through the sidebar and detail pane.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2026-07-07">
      <description>
        <p>0.3.0 "Full Ledger" — Auto-generated entry keys with live duplicate feedback, categories replacing the old `type` field, a Date Type dropdown (Single/Range/Ongoing) with separate Start/End fields, a first-run Field Guide, and a spreadsheet bulk-edit view (removed in 0.3.1).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.0" date="2026-07-07">
      <description>
        <p>0.2.0 "First Etching" — First packaged release. GTK4/libadwaita editor: sidebar with search/type/tag filtering, structured entry form with a dynamic type-specific fields editor, raw YAML toggle, add/duplicate/delete with delete confirmation, Manage Tags dialog with rename/merge, and a configurable data file location.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
